EPISODE 8
Masters.
Our Madam urged us to bring you the books,
lest we hinder your studies.
She also said that academic studies
might be important.
But Mr. Sang,
you just got over a long illness.
Please take care of yourself
and don't rush it.
See? What did I tell you?
Please thank Madam Li for me.
T-this is…?
Sorry, that was a mistake.
- This is not for you.
- Wait.
Luxuriant Dew of the Spring
and Autumn Annals. Volume 17.
All the copies I found
in the Xiangguo Temple book market
were missing the last two pages.
Where did you get this from?
- I…
- Listen, Chunlai.
May I keep it for a few days and return it
after I copy the last two pages?
That's not up to me.
I must go back and ask…
Ask whom?
Our third lady.
Her literary matchmaking failed,
and she gave you a donkey in the end.
And she plays the flute.
Stop gossiping.
I'll tell our madam to punish you.
Please allow me
to ask our third lady for permission.
But…
Wait.
If you know her, please go talk to her.
She holds a grudge against me.
She would kick me out if I went there.
I don't care. I want the book.
Hurry up and go.
Master, what are you…?
I ruined her engagement,
and now I'm asking her for a book.
If I don't get the book,
considering Andao's obsession with books,
I won't hear the end of it.
But I really think
I'll get a good beating if I talk to her.
It's all Master Chai's fault.
Master, I'm truly sorry.
There she is.
Hurry. Shouhua has been waiting.
Slow down. Watch your step.
So well wrapped. What is this?
Yuanming.
It's freezing out here.
Why are you reading outdoors?
Are you expecting someone?
Who would visit me?
It's just that
the room is warm and makes me drowsy.
I feel more awake out here.
Gentlemen, please come in.
Yuanming, why did you return
what we sent you?
Why do you insist
on returning those things?
Don't get us wrong.
Sang Andao is eccentric and peculiar.
He says that receiving gifts for no reason
might damage our luck on the exam.
Besides, we can't
accept rewards without merits.
Are you suspecting me
of bribing you before you even
become officials?
These are just some clothes.
They don't cost much.
You know Yuanming.
He didn't befriend us for material gains.
A pure friendship lasts the longest.
Don't you see?
Although he lives here,
he doesn't take anything
from the Li family.
Mr. Chai knows me the best.
That's my friend.
You, oh you.
Master Du.
Our third lady says
that ambergris comes from the far west.
It's a rare gift from someone.
We even sent it to a shop
to embed it with jade. It's very valuable.
Thankfully, you found and returned it
and saved us from trouble.
We can't repay your noble deed.
We only have a set of ink and inkstone,
which comes in handy for writing.
Please kindly accept it.
Everyone says the ink
made by Pan Gu of Shezhou
is the best.
Very few know that the fancy inks
outside the Xiangguo Temple
are mostly fake.
Look.
It's made
by the Ink Immortal with his trademark.
Right here.
Let me see.
This inkstone also looks fancy.
PLUM BLOSSOMS MINGLED WITH FALLING SNOW
Our third lady also said
it once belonged to our master.
It's a pity to let it lie in dust.
If you do not accept it,
she can only repay you with money.
Accept it.
You found her ambergris,
which is more precious than gold.
It's a token of gratitude.
So, you've earned it. Just accept it.
Then, please thank
your third lady for me, Chunlai.
How did it slip from my hands?
That was a top-quality Dengni inkstone.
What a shame.
Brother, that was such a fine inkstone.
Why were you so careless?
Listen, Yuanming, relax.
I will compensate you with my inkstone
made from Qingzhou Hongsi stone.
Don't bother with this one.
LUXURIANT DEW OF THE SPRING
AND AUTUMN ANNALS
Chunlai, please thank your third lady.
Brother, why are you
pulling a long face again?
Wait. I need to talk to you.
Dig in.
Betting on both sides.
Be careful. You may end up
winning nothing.
Kangning, it's freezing.
Better head back inside.
What's wrong?
You failed?
It was almost done.
But I didn't expect that Mr. Chai
would drop the fine inkstone.
He did?
Yes, he did.
Kangning.
I told you to take action in his absence
to avoid any disturbance.
This person harbors ill intentions.
You've been carving that all night.
He did well.
I won't blame him.
I must thank him, instead.
Thank you.
Plum blossoms mingled with falling snow.
How many flowers bloom upon the trees?
Truly one must drink to the full,
hoping that the like-minded will join.
Well-formed verses showing appreciation.
So much affection.
Li Kangning, you're going
to great lengths for Du Yangxi.
So, Kangning did this…
I see. My mother-in-law fancies him.
Makes sense.
He truly stands out from the rest
with his appearance and talent.
Whoever marries him
may be respected
as the wife of a top scholar one day.
Who wouldn't be tempted?
Brother, actually,
I'm here to persuade you
on your mother's behalf.
If you don't want to get beaten,
hold your tongue.
Auntie promised
not to bring up anyone you dislike again.
It's just that there is a family
that matches the Chai family
with their wealth.
The daughter of that family
is graceful and demure.
And you've grown up together
as childhood sweethearts.
It would be nice if you could get married.
Both your families could prosper.
You know her. It's Liu Baniang.
Who?
You know her.
She's Liu Tang's daughter.
You used to call her "little sister".
- Her?
- That's right.
How did I forget about her?
Speaking of which,
I haven't seen her for two years.
We should totally meet up.
Brother, I'm glad you've come around.
I'll tell Auntie right away
to arrange a meeting for you.
Wait for me.
Li Kangning.
This time, you can't blame me.
Even heaven is working against you.
Who are you? Let go of me.
Who are you?
Let go. Untie me.
Untie me.
You may leave.
- Understood.
You abducted me.
If my wife asks, you must testify for me.
I didn't sneak away.
I told you not to tease him.
Look how you've scared him.
Brother, help. Untie me.
Brother, untie me.
Baniang invited you over
with good intentions.
Who on earth invites guests like this?
I was startled.
Master Fan, please don't be mad.
Chai An told me that
you were confined at home by your wife
to study the account books.
So, that was my last resort.
If your wife asks about it one day,
just blame it on me.
You make it sound so easy.
What if she asks,
"Why would
a single young lady abduct you
and not someone else?
Is there something between you?"
What am I supposed to say?
Tell me.
Brother, let's get to business.
Baniang invited you to ask for a favor.
Thanks to Master Chai,
we found a great physician
who managed to cure my long illness.
I just recovered.
Why are you coughing now?
It's because
I've been copying the book for you.
How much debt
did I owe you from a past life?
Alright, I'll return it.
LUXURIANT DEW OF THE SPRING
AND AUTUMN ANNALS
Fine, return it yourself.
Catch a glimpse of Li Kangning
for the sake
of the enchanting flute sound.
The Fan family invited me over
to paint this afternoon.
I need to do a draft first.
Go away. Leave me alone.
The Fan family?
Maybe it's Li Kangning's excuse
to see you?
Really?
Leshan really loves to be different.
So much fuss over wontons.
Dough made with plum blossoms water.
And the wontons must be cooked
in chicken soup, right?
Mother was jealous
of Madam Liang's tea shop.
With the Winter Solstice approaching,
she thought wontons would sell.
But I think it's too much of a fuss.
Make different fillings
and cook everything in one pot.
I bet Hundred Flavor Wontons
will sell the best.
That would be nice.
But it's not as elegant as plum blossoms.
I'm afraid the scholars next door
won't be impressed.
What? Say it again.
At midday,
Master's servant Fan Jiu
opened the back door
and led a young lady inside.
Well, well.
I've only been out for a moment
and he's been
bringing ladies into the house.
He never learns his lesson.
- Step aside.
- Fuhui.
Kangning. There might be trouble.
Keep an eye on her.
Fuhui.
FAN'S MANSION
Brother.
I'm taking a huge risk by helping you.
I let an unmarried lady into the house.
If my wife finds out,
she will skin me alive.
Liu Baniang is only meeting someone here.
Do you have to be so anxious?
Why here and not at your place?
I am a married man.
She is a single lady.
When did we ever become acquainted?
How do I explain that?
If my wife finds out,
she's going to lose it out of jealousy.
You're not the one who's going to suffer.
The Chai and Liu families
are discussing a marital alliance.
She can't go to my place.
That's why she came here.
Besides, I'm here to defend you.
Masters, the painter has arrived.
I have sent her over
as you instructed, Master Chai.
- Good job. You may leave now.
- Understood.
I hope Liu Baniang
can vent her anger and leave soon.
Don't let my wife run into her.
Brother, I'm afraid I have to
sacrifice you this time.
Stop right there.
You're back, my lady.
Let me inform my master.
No need. I'll find who I'm looking for.
We'll settle this later on.
- My lady.
- Fuhui.
My lady.
Fuhui, slow down.
- My lady, our master is not there.
- Listen to me.
Fuhui.
My lady, our master is not in the study.
Come with me.
Master Chai, what are you doing?
Let go.
Don't you want to know
what kind of person Du Yangxi is?
Please hide in there.
Master Du will be here?
I am an honest man.
Have I ever lied to you?
I'm only trying
to expose someone's true nature.
I will not hurt you.
Besides, we're in the Fan's mansion.
- But--
- Cats hide their claws.
How can you marry someone
without knowing his true colors?
Kangning, I am trying to help you.
Please.
Get up.
Hurry.
My wife is looking for me. Be quiet.
My lady, please be careful.
Lady Liu.
Why did you corner me here?
What exactly do you want?
I want to talk things through with you.
Master Du, you haven't told me
why you turned me down.
I'm a humble man of modest ability
and mediocre talent.
I don't deserve a lady like you.
Nonsense.
I bet you refused to marry me
because you looked down upon my family
for being merchants
and wanted to marry
into a distinguished family
to cling to real power in the court.
Then why are you living
next door to the Li family
and thinking about marrying Li Kangning?
There is no such thing.
As a Juren who came for the imperial exam,
you're living next
to a family with five daughters
without avoiding the ladies.
How dare you deny it?
Lady Liu.
It's my own business,
no matter whether
it's true or not.
If you favor a lady
from a distinguished family
due to your pride and ambition,
then I accept the fact
that we're not meant to be.
And it's fine by me.
But you chose Li Kangning over me.
Then I must ask.
Ask what?
Is it because they are wealthy
or that they offer a huge dowry?
Even if she is pretty,
am I much uglier than her?
Even if she is talented,
do I look dumb to you?
Master Du.
Look closely.
Am I inferior to her?
No.
You are perfect as you are.
But marriage is predestined.
It can't be forced.
I don't care if you turn me down.
But you're buttering them up
while rejecting me.
You're clearly humiliating me.
Everyone in Bianjing will think
Li Kangning is better than me.
Even a Juren who has not
passed the imperial exam
dares to deceive me,
abandon me, and humiliate me.
Don't even think about leaving
if you don't give me
an explanation.
Fine.
You want an explanation.
I will give you one.
There are three things
I don't value in taking a wife.
First, her family background.
Second, the dowry she offers.
Third, her looks and talents.
I come from a humble background,
living a tough life alone
with my widowed mother for 20 years.
Others won't understand that.
Daughters of officials and rich merchants
are mostly arrogant and spoiled.
Can they treat my elderly poor mother
with kindness and respect?
No, they can't.
Even if your wealth
rivals that of Shi Chong
and you are as beautiful as a fairy,
you're not the "Meng Guang" I seek.
Fan Lianghan.
There is no one in there.
Oh no.
Why is she back?
- If she sees us like this…
- Fan Lianghan.
- …I'll have to marry you.
- Where are you?
Master Fan is way too useless.
Are they in there? Step aside.
No, there's no one inside.
Fan Lianghan.
Come out.
- Fan Lianghan.
- My lady.
My lady, I swear there's no one inside.
No one? Then who is she?
Do you take me for a blind or a fool?
How dare you fool me?
Fan Lianghan, you'd better come out now.
It will be worse for you if I catch you.
I'll open the door
and tell her everything.
Liu Baniang.
Who asked Master Fan
to invite me over to paint?
Well…
Still not coming out?
Do I have to search in person?
Fan Lianghan, come out.
Fan Lianghan.
Are you coming out or not?
Fan Lianghan, I'll count to three.
Hide. Go.
- Hurry.
- Fan Lianghan.
Hurry.
Get in.
I have a clear conscience.
- Why should I hide?
- Fan Lianghan.
Please do this for me.
I'm begging you. Get in.
Open up, Fan Lianghan.
Get in.
Yuanming, suit yourself.
Fan Lianghan, open up.
Mr. Chai, what a surprise.
- Fan Lianghan.
- I know what to do.
Okay.
Fan Lianghan.
I know you're in there.
Open up.
My lady, he jumped out the window.
- Useless.
Fuhui, please calm down.
Fuhui, there's a reason for this.
It's my fault. Don't blame him.
Find him first.
Have a proper talk.
You'll figure it out.
Yuanming.
Mr. Chai.
What you did
was really not honorable.
Yuanming, the Chai and Liu families
have long been friends.
And Baniang begged me for help.
I had no choice.
Please forgive me.
I was hiding there
just in case Baniang acted on a whim.
I'm really sorry that we disturbed you.
I will apologize to you formally.
Housekeeper.
Before Fuhui comes back,
hurry up and leave.
- Escort Master Du out.
- Master Du, please.
Yuanming, hurry.
You set me up.
It was such a mess.
You owe me an explanation.
Baniang.
I did all this
to let you talk to Master Du.
You've misunderstood me.
Let's discuss the details later.
Go home first. Hurry.
- I'm dead.
- Master.
I'm dead.
Master, don't be afraid. It's me.
Those two have left.
My lady can't catch them.
That's good.
Who said I was hiding from her?
Why should I be scared?
Even if she is standing right here,
I will…
What will you do?
I made a silly mistake.
As long as I get on my knees and repent,
how can my sweetheart scold me or hit me?
Am I right, honey?
Get up.
- You may leave.
- Understood.
Fuhui.
My brother asked me to do this.
Du Yangxi turned down
Liu Baniang for no reason.
She felt humiliated
and insisted on confronting him.
My brother made me do this.
Look at you.
You make it so much worse by saying that.
You did everything
your brother told you to do.
Don't you know that my mother wants
Du Yangxi to marry into our family?
Have you thought about Kangning?
You always listen to your brother
and never care about me.
How dare you keep me in the dark?
Come here.
Ouch, honey.
Be gentle, honey. It hurts.
Kangning.
What Du Yangxi said might sound sincere,
but it's not completely true.
Ladies from wealthy families
can also uphold filial piety
and moral principles.
I bet he only wants someone
from a poor family for other reasons.
He may fool Liu Baniang,
but he can't fool you.
Your evaluation of Master Du
is entirely speculative
without any solid evidence.
Besides, everyone has their own destiny.
It has nothing to do with him
that we're no longer engaged.
Leave him alone.
It has everything to do with him.
Kangning, you promised to marry me.
You keep pestering me,
unwilling to give up,
merely out of pride
and your reluctance to admit defeat.
You have your pride.
I have my integrity.
I suggest you let be it.
Don't hold on to it.
If he was a nice guy, I would let go.
But judging from what he said and did,
he clearly has ulterior motives.
You can't entrust yourself to him.
No way.
I won't allow it.
Go back. I know what to do.
- Go. Hurry.
- Chai An.
Chai An, since when did you
get to decide my marriage?
Hurry up.
You're too bossy.
Chai An.
Take her home.
Did he really say that?
Judging someone's character
in just a few words
is truly absurd.
Who knows if he's jealous
and trying to destroy your marriage
with some lies?
Master Chai is not that kind of person.
But those two have been living next door
for a long time.
Shouhua, you've read his poems and essays.
Didn't you praise him for his insight
and talent?
You even imitate his writing
because it conceals vigor and spirit.
Even if they are bandits or criminals,
we have neither wealth nor power.
What would they want from us?
Kangning, what do you say?
I can't see through this person.
But it doesn't have to be him.
Isn't there another candidate?
No way.
Forget about it. It won't work.
What hair oil do you use?
I…
Top-quality osmanthus hair oil.
That was the first time I saw a man
throwing up due to the smell of hair oil.
He deserves to remain single forever.
Don't tell anyone about
what happened with Master Du yet.
Don't tell our mother either.
Time reveals people's hearts.
If there is something wrong with him,
we'll find out about it.
Let's wait a bit.
Your mother and I are best friends.
You would follow her here
when you were a kid and run behind An'er.
I haven't seen you for years.
You've grown into such a stunning beauty.
So dazzling.
I heard you often traveled
with your father.
He is so muddle-headed.
How can he let you run around in public
in the prime of youth?
Now, Chai An has grown up.
Your mother mentioned it to me yesterday.
Fine, I'll stop right here.
I'll discuss it with your mother.
Madam, the young master is back.
Mother.
An'er, you've come back just in time.
Sit with Baniang.
The servants don't know
what Baniang likes.
I will tell them what snacks to get.
Don't bother, Mother. Let me do it.
Let me do it.
You grew up together
like siblings. Don't be shy.
- Mother.
- Sit down.
Deqing.
Chai An, you said you would do me justice,
but in fact, you served your own purpose.
Du Yangxi outright refused you,
which made you upset for a long time.
You insisted on seeing him,
so I helped out.
I just brought along another onlooker,
but I helped you,
so you have to help me too.
You're always straightforward.
Why do you mind it?
You…
You're really going to lengths
for Li Kangning.
But I can tell
that your mother wants me
as her daughter-in-law.
I'm afraid all your efforts
have been in vain.
Baniang.
You've seen the painting
and met him in person.
Du Yangxi truly stands out
with his literary grace and charm.
Aren't you any attracted?
My marriage is entirely up to my parents.
I'm just a young lady.
I have no say in this matter.
- Alright then, forget it.
- Chai An.
You have an idea?
This man is quite elusive.
But we're not a powerless
ordinary family in Bianjing.
Even if he has a thousand tricks,
I can deal with them.
What is there to fear?
But your mother wants
a marital alliance so badly.
How is Du Yangxi…
As long as you follow my plan,
within ten days,
my mother will change her mind.
Even Master Du will turn to pursue you.
- Deal.
PAN RESTAURANT
- This is infuriating. That diviner!
- Sister.
It was just a divination.
Why did you get enraged?
Mr. Wang, the diviner,
said that the Chai and Liu families
couldn't form a marital alliance.
And he dared to curse my son
with a life of solitude.
I was magnanimous
for not smashing his things
on the spot.
But he read your fortune
and wrote down what had happened to you.
Everything he wrote was accurate.
I bet he learned those from Lianghan.
Even your son doesn't know
that you went missing when you were six
and were found later.
How can the diviner cheat?
He's just wrong.
No one can ruin the marriage
between my son and Liu Baniang.
I must try someone else.
Madam.
Has Lady Liu arrived?
The Liu family said
that the shaft of Lady Liu's carriage
broke right after she left home.
Lady Liu thought it was a bad sign,
so she headed back
and sent someone to apologize.
What? It broke?
You see?
Madam, bad news.
- An'er.
- Mother.
An'er, what's happened?
How did you get hurt?
I was coming back from work.
The horse went crazy
and started running wild
for no reason.
Thankfully, no one else was hurt.
Mother, don't worry.
It's nothing serious.
Hurry. Apply some medicine.
That's right. Hurry up.
- Find a physician.
- Understood.
I hope you do not take offense.
Your son is afflicted by the Lonely Star.
His marital fate suffers.
Even if you find him a wife,
in as little as one month
or half a year tops,
a calamity will surely befall.
There will be blood.
There was someone
with great energy in her fortune
that could suppress his Lonely Star.
It's a pity
that the marital tie was severed
before it was formed.
It's both timing and fate.
Oh no.
I shouldn't have canceled the engagement.
You are truly ruthless.
How did you manage to do this?
The wound looks terrifying.
Madam watched
the physician give a prescription
and left in a hurry.
We don't know where she went.
I know where she went.
Any news from the people I sent to Ezhou?
A message has come.
The person was found and put on a boat.
- Do not come again.
- Madam Li.
- Go away.
- Get out.
Take these back.
The Chai family is wealthy
and influential,
with good farmland and great business.
Their wealth and honor are unmatched.
My family only runs a small tea stall
with one storefront.
We're no match for them in social status.
The son of the Chai family
is the best young man in the world.
He's one of a kind.
But my daughter is just a village girl
who lacks proper upbringing and manners.
She's no match for that young man.
Whoever wants to cling
to this wealthy and powerful family,
go ahead.
Even if they come begging me,
- I won't bother seeing them.
- Madam Li.
Madam Chai deeply regrets her decision.
She has long changed her mind.
So, she sent us here to apologize,
hoping that
you'll overlook past grievances and renew
the marital tie between the two families.
She is totally sincere.
Such nice in-laws are hard to find.
Even if you are holding a grudge,
you should think about your daughter.
Yeah, take a look.
These are all good stuff.
Good stuff?
What good stuff?
They despise the poor
and admire the rich.
They're the worst of the worst.
The worst.
When I marry off my daughter,
I won't care about status or wealth.
I will find her a good family
valuing education and integrity.
The Chai family came back
to ask for my daughter?
In their dreams!
Go away.
Take it away!
Madam Li.
- Madam Li.
- If you dare to come again,
I'll kick you out! Close the door.
Madam Li.
Madam Li. Open up.
Why did they close the door?
- Madam Li.
You always outshine bright colors.
Beautiful.
Your goose-yellow gown is also pretty.
It looks cheerful in winter.
But the waist is a bit loose.
Mother wants to fill the quilts
with new cotton for our neighbors.
I was too busy to modify my clothes.
Give it to me. I'll help.
Just don't get your hair oil on it.
Or someone may end up puking in his sleep.
That's going to be tiring.
The Chai family came back
to ask for my daughter?
In their dreams!
Close the door. Get lost.
Shouhua, I only improvised the "get lost".
The rest are her exact words.
Why didn't you pay attention?
You didn't see
our mother's awe-inspiring stance.
So imposing.
They deserve it.
Why did the Chai family
put on air and bully us
in the beginning?
He first invited Kangning to eavesdrop
and made Madam Chai change her mind.
Master Chai seems determined
to win Kangning back at all costs.
But it's not easy to change the mindset
of disdaining the poor.
If Madam Chai
changes her mind again one day,
then our family
will be utterly humiliated.
Mr. Chai is so used
to calling the shots alone.
He decides to get engaged and back out
whenever he wants,
treating me like his pet or toy,
who doesn't have a say.
I will decide whom to marry.
If he insists on meddling,
then I won't let him off.
You've seen the fanciest accessories.
I wouldn't dare offer anything ordinary.
I handpicked the special ones
just for you.
This cloisonné flower tube hairpin
may seem simple,
but the flare is great
for holding flowers.
You…
We've received so many proposals
from Bianjing,
even to the Daming prefecture.
I'm so swamped.
Here are their birthdays.
Please take a look and find the best fit.
Madam.
XINHAI JIAXU YISI GUISI
Li Kangning. I knew it.
It is the will of heaven.
Even the parents shall not resist it.
If you don't take my advice…
What if I don't take your advice?
- Turn this upside down.
- Wait.
Please don't.
- Capture him.
- Please don't.
I tested you to see if you were authentic.
You wrote a few lines
and dropped the paper.
Then you asked me about my past.
Even if you didn't get anything right,
the boy under the table would fix it.
How could it not be accurate?
It's nothing but a lie!
Madam Chai.
Master Chai orchestrated this.
I just did what he told me to do.
My lady, please spare me.
Madam Chai, please spare me.
FINE WINE PRODUCED BY PAN RESTAURANT
DELICACIES AND TOP QUALITY DRINKS
Master.
Gentlemen, please come in.
I see.
Bring the horse. I'm going to the port.
Hurry up.
But what about Madam?
Let her be.
Master.
Master, I rushed to the port
as you ordered, but nobody was there.
You didn't find her?
What about the guards?
Liu's merchant ship
should have arrived by midday,
but I saw no trace of the ship.
I didn't want to keep you waiting,
so I told the others to stay
and came back alone.
Oh no.
Liu Baniang.
Why did you go back on your word?
You agreed to my plan.
Yet you sold me out.
What makes you say that?
The diviner has been in this profession
for over a decade
and rarely slips up.
But my mother saw through his tricks.
Before that, she had been
scammed out of a fortune every year.
The person I found should have arrived
but vanished.
And it just happened
that they boarded your merchant ship.
Liu Baniang. Tell me. Where is she?
Chai An.
Sorry, I have let you down.
She's with the Li family?
- Welcome our guest.
- Understood.
Madam Du, please step out of the sedan.
Master Du is good-looking,
graceful, and elegant.
How come his mother looks like this?
Haode, why do you sound so judgmental?
That's not what I meant.
They don't look alike.
MADAM DU
She doesn't look like his mother.
She's more like his grandmother.
Let's go.
Sister, here.
Please enjoy.
You're too kind. How do I deserve this?
Here's the spoon.
Be careful. It's hot.
Good girl.
Thank you.
What did Li Kangning offer you?
She told me…
If you marry Master Du,
even if he passes the exam
and gets appointed to the Hanlin Academy
or to an external post,
his salary will be meager,
and you'll live a modest life.
It may be fine to use up your dowry,
but you may have to imitate
Meng Guang from ancient times,
remove all the accessories,
change into worn-out clothes,
and look after your mother-in-law.
How can a single young lady
say such things?
Merchants value profit over anything else.
I can't say such things to the others.
But I can to you.
But I can't marry Chai An either.
He is so shrewd.
I won't be able
to take any advantage of him.
Except for scholars and cunning merchants,
don't you have other options?
She changed your mind
with just a few words?
I don't believe it.
Who did she recommend?
All my elder sisters are married.
My younger brother is only nine.
I'll get a lot more
if someone marries into my family.
Thankfully, Kangning reminded me.
I didn't see the whole picture.
The problem is you won't make it.
Let's see whether she teaches you
how to convince your father
to keep you at home.
My dear brother.
Merchants often pursue profit
over righteousness.
I grew up observing what the merchants do
and learned to be
obsessed with wealth better than anyone.
It's not that I want to betray you.
It's really just my nature.
Whoever offers me the most benefits,
I will naturally follow their lead
without any second thoughts.
Well played, Li Kangning.
How dare you stab me in my back?
Despicable.
So despicable.
Chai An?
Chai An!
Subtitle translation by: Jie Chen